<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nick Gavalas</title>
    <link>https://nickgavalas.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nick Gavalas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nickgavalas.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection on data streams, in one line of Bash</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/anomaly-detection-on-data-streams-in-one-line-of-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/anomaly-detection-on-data-streams-in-one-line-of-bash/</guid>
      <description>During the writing of my master thesis, I studied thoroughly Anomaly Detection algorithms with a focus on those of them that could be deployed not only on batches, but on streams of data, in order to achieve real-time Anomaly Detection, on a big scale.
After research, I chose 5 algorithms with such capabilities that looked promising, studied the relevant papers and understood how they worked. I then proceeded to implement each one, run it on a cluster (with the help of Apache Flink) with real and synthetic datasets, and find out the strenghts and weaknesses of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH: How to prevent MITM attacks</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/ssh-how-to-prevent-mitm-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/ssh-how-to-prevent-mitm-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Consider the following scenario: You connect to some remote machine for the first time via SSH, and you get the following message:
nick@sapphire: $ ssh &amp;lt;host&amp;gt; The authenticity of host &#39;&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;&#39; can&#39;t be established. ECDSA key fingerprint is SHA256:I9Uxj/t8o1tSpfnA/II1BJqvMw8eELmLhRQAylPL7Lk. Are you sure you want to continue connecting (yes/no)?  The SSH client gives you the SHA256 hash of the remote host&amp;rsquo;s public key (its fingerprint) and asks you to verify that the host you are attempting to connect to is indeed the one you want to connect to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the Multiple Choice Knapsack Problem</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/solving-the-multiple-choice-knapsack-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/solving-the-multiple-choice-knapsack-problem/</guid>
      <description>The 0-1 Knapsack problem is a popular combinatorial optimization problem:
 Given a set of n items, each having a value \( p_i \) and a weight of \( w_i \), find a subset of these items such that the total value is maximized, while keeping the total weight of the items under a given constant weight capacity W.
 Formally, we need to maximize \( \sum_{i=1}^{n}{p_{i}f_{i}} \), while subjecting to \( \sum_{i=1}^{n}{w_{i}f_{i}} \le W \), \( f_i \in \{0, 1\}, \forall i \in \{ 1, &amp;hellip;, n\} \).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible hostvars JSON querying with JMESPath</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/ansible-hostvars-json-querying-with-jmespath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/ansible-hostvars-json-querying-with-jmespath/</guid>
      <description>I was writing an ansible playbook to deploy an Apache Flink cluster, and I ran into this problem while editing the configuration files:
 How can I get the total number of the vCPUs of all the &amp;ldquo;slave&amp;rdquo; machines running on the cluster?
 I thought of the hostvars ansible variable, which stores the gathered facts about the hosts, so using the debug module, I printed it out. The result was a JSON like that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building networks with FreeBSD (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/building-networks-with-freebsd-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/building-networks-with-freebsd-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the second part of my tutorial series. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to use the Quagga Software Suite for dynamic routing.
The dynamic routing protocols we &amp;rsquo;ll use are the most widely used today: RIP, OSPF and BGP.
For some details on what these protocols are used for, and how they work, you can take a look at this post.
At the end of the post you will find details for the IPv6 versions of these protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building networks with FreeBSD (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/building-networks-with-freebsd-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/building-networks-with-freebsd-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my tutorial series for using the FreeBSD OS and the Quagga software routing suite for building network architectures.
I hope this series serves a good reference point for anyone interested in examining and getting hands-on experience with the routing protocols and network topologies. However I won&amp;rsquo;t be going into the details on how the protocols work.
To emulate the needed hardware for testing purposes, I &amp;rsquo;m using VirtualBox, and I recommend it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Primer</title>
      <link>https://nickgavalas.com/docker-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickgavalas.com/docker-primer/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this little article when I was learning about Docker, to use it for self reference. But then I thought that other beginners may find it useful too, so why not post it on my blog?
So let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it.
What is Docker? If you already have an idea about what docker is, and why it&amp;rsquo;s userful, skip this part.
Docker is a platform that allows you to run your applications in an isolated environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>